

Gian Pietro Farina

Doctoral Candidate at SUNY - University at Buffalo Graduation Date: Feb 2020

Graduation Date. Feb 2020

337 Longmeadow Rd, 14226 Buffalo, NY

+1 7163354608

www.gianpietrofarina.com

git https://github.com/gpfarina

farinagianpietro@gmail.com

3072R/E07677EB

Languages

Italian

English



About Me -

Passionate for sciences, technology and philosphy. I am currently finishing my Ph.D in Computer Science at University at Buffalo. In my research I build tools to help developers discover bugs in their programs, especially bugs which might lead to security breaches: e.g. violations of Differential Privacy and Noninterference. The techinques I most frequently use are: type systems, Hoare logics, and symbolic execution.

Working Experience

05/2019- 08/2019		Harvard University symbolic execution engine for R pro-					
01/2019- 05/2019	grams for Differential Privacy Long Term Visitor Data Privacy: Foundations a	Simons Institute - UC Berkeley					
2015-2018	Teaching Assistant University at Buffalo & Dundee Introduction to Programming Languages (2018), Advanced Topics in Programming Languages (2017), Differential Privacy (2016), Introduction to Data Mining and Machine Learning(2015)						
03/2014- 12/2014	Penetration Tester Experience with OWASP me Suite, NESSUS, mimikatz, Wi	Accenture, Prague ethodology, ESXi, vSphere, Kali, Burp-ireshark					
10/2013- 02/2014		st (Internship) LUTECH, Milano n, Elasticsearch, Kibana, SNORT, statis- al Anomaly Detection					
10/2012- 10/2013	Cryptography Researcher Research on Black Box Redu dom Oracle Model	ETH, Zurich ctions and Meta Reductions in the Ran-					
01/2012- 08/2012		Aalto University, Helsinki Ciphers PRESENT and Maya and test for ack (SSA) on the Block Cipher PRESENT					

Programming Languages and Verification Tools

~	Java	•	•	•	•	•	NuSMV Model Checker	•	•	•	•	
~	oCaml						Java Path Finder					
~	С						✓ TLA+					
~	R						✓ Coq					

Education

University at Dundee → SUNY - University at Buffalo Formal verification of probabilistic relational properties, e.g. differential privacy

Computer Science, Master Degree (110/110 cum Laude)

Università di Milano

Computer Science, Bachelor Degree (110/110 cum Laude)

Alma Mater Università di Bologna

Publications

Coupled Relational Symbolic Execution - CONF 2020, Relational Symbolic Execution - PPDP 2019, Differentially Private Bayesian Programming - CCS 2016, PrivInfer: A framework for differentially private Bayesian Programming - poster at TPDP 2016, Towards differentially private probabilistic programming - poster at NIPS 2014

Interests and Hobbies

2015-Present Doctorate in Computer Science

Programming Languages Theory and Applications, Verification, Security, Differential Privacy, Testing, Philosophy, Cooking, Football, Arts